Seema A

Pune, Maharashtra, India



ahirebn1@rediffmail.com



linkedin.com/in/seema-a-b633b756

Summary

#6+ years of experience in Cloud and Kubernetes platform.

Kubernetes Engineer with 3 years of hands-on experience in designing, automating and monitoring application deployment processes.

Experience in maintaining, deploying and managing cloud services.

Used Kubernetes to orchestrate the deployment, scaling and management of Docker Containers.

Hands-on experience on installation and setting up Docker and Kubernetes cluster on AWS.

Experience



Cloud Engineer

Confidential

Oct 2016 - Present (6 years 7 months)

Working with container-based deployments using Docker, working with Docker Images, Docker Hub and Docker-registries and Kubernetes.

Working on container management tool Kubernetes. Created Kubernetes clusters for microservices deployment, managing pods, replica sets,

Kubernetes networking, ingress, and load balancers.

Based on client requirement scaling and management of Deployments.

Installing and configuring Kubernetes dashboard UI.

Creating and managing Pods, Deployments, services, Volumes using Kubernetes CLI.

Responsible for health checking and optimization of Kubernetes components.

Responsible for implementation and ongoing administration of Kubernetes infrastructure.

Utilizing Kubernetes and Docker for the runtime environment of the CI/CD system to build, test, and deploy.

Implementing a security module using RBAC and creating CA and TLS Certificates for Kubernetes cluster using OpenSSL.

Continuous monitoring of K8s cluster and node logs through Kubernetes Dashboard/ Prometheus and Grafana.

Cloud resource provision using Terraform.

Experience with Amazon Web Services (AWS) - EC2, VPC, S3, IAM, EBS, and EKS.

Oracle DBA

Tech Mahindra

Apr 2012 - Sep 2016 (4 years 6 months)

L1 Production Support

Tech Mahindra Nov 2007 - Sep 2016 (8 years 11 months)

Education



Pune University

Bachelor of Commerce 1994 - 1997

Skills

Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Microsoft Azure • Kubernetes • Amazon EKS • Terraform • Git • Jenkins • Prometheus.io • Grafana